Gilman Family Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
- IV. George Shepard Gilman
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from Mary (Mrs. Julius S. Gilman)., 1885; (2 items) (Box 13, Folder P)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from Jane Gilman; from J.H. Knight., 1883-1885; (2 items) (Box 13, Folder Q)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from Nathan Morse., 1867-1877; (27 items) (Box 13, Folder Q-1)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from "Cousin" Mary [Simonten?]., 1845; (2 items) (Box 13, Folder R)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from J. Wadsworth, J.E. Terry., 1864-65; (6 items) (Box 13, Folder S)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from H. Barnard., 1845-1864; (3 items) (Box 13, Folder T)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from J.C. Cowell., 1848; (4 items) (Box 13, Folder U)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from Norman Gillette., 1845-46; (2 items) (Box 13, Folder V)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from J.R. Mork., 1846-49; (4 items) (Box 13, Folder W)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from Henry C. Robinson., 1848-57; (9 items) (Box 13, Folder X)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from H.L. Shute., 1847-49; (4 items) (Box 13, Folder Y)
  - Correspondence George Shepard Gilman from personal A-Z., 1848-86; (33 items) (Box 13, Folder Z)
  - Burial plot, George Shepard Gilman diagram., [18--?]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder A)
  - Discharge certificates Thomas Barret, 1813, Henry Blume, 1863., 1813 & 1863; (2 items) (Box 14, Folder B)
  - Beta Beta chapter, Psi Upsilon, books and correspondence., 1848-1890; (9 items) (Box 14, Folder C)
  - Notary Public appointment. by Governor Joseph Trumbull., 1849; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder C-1)
  - Draft exemption George Shepard Gilman., 1863; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder D)
  - South Congregational Church, Sabbath School, Library Fund., [18--?]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder E)
  - South Congregational Church, Organ Fund., 1884-85; (10 items) (Box 14, Folder F)
  - Second Ecclesiastical Society (South Church) and church bicentennial expenses, 1870; appointment Trustees., 1878 - 1885; (9) items) (Box 14, Folder G)
  - Farmington River Water Supply-Reports Joint Special Commission., 1878; (7 items) (Box 14, Folder H)
  - George Shepard Gilman racing cards., 1883-1885; (11 item) (Box 14, Folder I)
  - George Shepard Gilman Horse-buying tips., 1885; (4 items) (Box 14, Folder J)
  - Correspondence re horses., 1876-77; (15 items) (Box 14, Folder J-1)
  - Health remedies., 1870-1886; (5 items) (Box 14, Folder K)
  - American Temperance Life Insurance Co. petition., 1851; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder L)
  - Deeds, Mortgages, and relevant correspondence, A-Z., 1856-1875; (8 items) (Box 14, Folder M)
  - Receipts, goods, taxes, services., 1848-1868; (23 items) (Box 14, Folder N)
  - Correspondence re estates A-Z., 1863-69; (11 item) (Box 14, Folder 0)
  - Correspondence re investments White, Freitas, and Rathbone., 1868; (27 items) (Box 14, Folder 0-1)
  - Correspondence James M. Niles., 1867-1874; (45 items) (Box 14, Folder 0-2)
  - Legal cases, agreements, estates, petitions, claims., 1851-68; (29 items) (Box 14, Folder P)
  - Bonds Cincinnati, Wilmington and Zanesville R.R. Co., 1858; (50 items) (Box 14, Folder Q)
  - Tax receipts land in Minnesota, Nebraska and Wisconsin., 1861; (47 items) (Box 14, Folder R)
  - LORENZO, Frank Fuller, estate., 1851-56; (30 items) (Box 14, Folder S)
  - WHITE, W.H., Estate: bills and receipts., 1855-56; (22 items) (Box 14, Folder T)
  - KILBY, Henry, Estate: receipts and promissory notes., 1856-57; (34 items) (Box 14, Folder U)
  - MALLEY, James, Bankruptcy., 1856-57; (34 items) (Box 14, Folder V)
  - SCHUE, John, Estate., 1856-59; (22 items) (Box 14, Folder W)
  - SHULTAS, Elizabeth, Estate; receipts., 1857-61; (2 items) (Box 14, Folder X)
  - Wisconsin lands deeds., 1857; (3 items) (Box 14, Folder Y)
  - Thornton Sewing machine patent; sale manufacturing rights., 1859; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder Z)
  - Brig Scotland damage case., 1861; (3 items) (Box 14, Folder AA)
  - Promissory notes., 1861-79; (12 items) (Box 14, Folder BB)
  - Michael Chauncey estate., 1863-73; (141 item) (Box 14a, Folder A-G)
  - George Shepard Gilman directorships, appointments and meetings., 1862-64; (6 items) (Box 15, Folder A)
  - STEVENS, J. Strickland, estate: receipts., 1862; (6 items) (Box 15, Folder B)
  - Chatfield, Minnesota, Land investments, correspondence., 1863-1884; (170 items) (Box 15, Folder C-G-3)
  - Chatfield, Minnesota, Land investments, notes; deeds, statements., 1863-77; (12 items) (Box 15, Folder H)
  - Chatfield, Minnesota, Land investments accounts., 1865-1881; (16 items) (Box 15, Folder H-1)
  - Chatfield, Minnesota, Land investments, tax receipts., 1862; (12 items) (Box 15, Folder H-2)
  - GILMAN, Eli estate: sale land in Indiana., 1864; (3 items) (Box 15, Folder I)
  - Sage Ammunition Works, Middletown, Connecticut: Correspondence., 1864-1865; (11 item) (Box 15, Folder J)
  - Sage Ammunition Works sale., 1865-69; (11 item) (Box 15, Folder K)
  - Naugatuck Valley Peat Co. Articles of Association., 1866; (4 items) (Box 15, Folder L)
  - COGGESHALL, D.D., Estate, receipts., 1870-74; (54 items) (Box 15, Folder M)
  - NOTT and GILMAN, account sheets., 1870-71; (4 items) (Box 15, Folder N)
  - BARNARD, John., Estate: bills to be paid., 1871-76; (15 items) (Box 15, Folder 0)
  - BARNARD, John., Estate:General bills., 1873-85; (57 items) (Box 15, Folder P)
  - BARNARD, John., Estate: Mortgages and notes., 1873-1885; 44 (Box 15, Folder Q)
  - BARNARD, John., Estate: Disbursements to relatives; receipts., 1873-1881; (73 items) (Box 15, Folder R)
  - BARNARD, John., Estate: Closing documents., 1885-86; (18 items) (Box 15, Folder S)
  - DUSTIN-GILMAN Co.: Bankruptcy., 1871-1877; (9 items) (Box 15, Folder T)
  - WELLS, Mary G., Mortgage notes., 1871-1877; (16 items) (Box 15, Folder U)
  - KING, H.M. family. Will, deed, correspondence., 1874-1880; (10 items) (Box 15, Folder V)
  - Ottawa, Illinois bonds, correspondence., 1874-76; (12 items) (Box 15, Folder W)
  - Agreement Sharp, Archer, Gilman and Hills for tobacco crop., 1875-76; (5 items) (Box 16, Folder A)
  - Connecticut Mutual Insurance Co.: agents bonds., 1875-83; 24 (Box 16, Folder B)
  - Russell, J.R. (broker]: Gilman account-ledger sheets., 1880-1882; (8 items) (Box 16, Folder C)
  - Doane, George Omaha, Nebraska: deeds, mortgages, related correspondence, includes letters from Alvin Saunders, Senator, Nebraska., 1877-1882; (20 items) (Box 16, Folder D)
  - Doane, George Omaha, Nebraska; mortgages., 1883-1885; (14 items) (Box 16, Folder E)
  - "City of Hartford" expenses and receipts., 1882; (4 items) (Box 16, Folder F)
  - Colorado Coal and Iron Co. Reorganization. Reports., 1880-87; 6 (Box 16, Folder G)
  - Colorado Coal and Iron Co. Reorganization. Denver and Rio Grande Railway. Reorganization correspondence., 33; (1882-86 items) (Box 16, Folder H)
  - Colorado Coal and Iron Co. Denver and Rio Grande Railway: Reports., 1882-87; (13 items) (Box 16, Folder I)
  - Morse, Nathan, estate, and related correspondence., 1883-4; (18 items) (Box 16, Folder J)
  - Miscellaneous railroad companies; correspondence and reports., 1882-87; (15 items) (Box 16, Folder K)
  - Connecticut Mutual Insurance Co. account sheets; business in Pennsylvania., 1884; (4 items) (Box 16, Folder L)
  - Connecticut Mutual Insurance Co. Correspondence., 1865-1886; (10 items) (Box 16, Folder M)
  - Gas meters and prices information., 1885; (5 items) (Box 16, Folder N)
  - Davenport and Bridges, mortgage note, Omaha, Nebraska., 1886-1888; (8 items) (Box 16, Folder 0)
  - Missouri, Kansas and Texas Railway reorganization., 1887-1880; (15 items) (Box 16, Folder P)
  - George Shepard Gilman estate documents., 1881-1916; (41 item) (Box 16, Folder Q-V)
  - BUCKINGHAM, William A. (Governor of Connecticut), correspondence to George Shepard Gilman re Republican campaign in Hartford County., March 14-Dec.20, 1860; (3 items) (Box 17, Folder A)
  - BUCKINGHAM, William, ALS to George Shepard Gilman Feb. 24, 1863 to April 9, 1864 and to Gen. B.F. Butler copies re. military promotions and passes., 1863-1864; (7 items) (Box 17, Folder B)
  - BUCKINGHAM, William A., Appointment George Shepard Gilman notary public., 1861,1864; (2 items) (Box 17, Folder C)
  - George Shepard Gilman from E.L. Cleveland., 1860; (1 item) (Box 17, Folder D)
  - George Shepard Gilman: to Edwin M. Stanton from Henry C. Deming introducing George Shepard Gilman., [186-?]; (2 items) (Box 17, Folder E)
  - GREELY, Horace ALS to George Shepard Gilman, re. invitation to speak., July 20, 22nd, 1860; (2 items) (Box 17, Folder F)
  - HAWLEY, Jos. R., ALS to George Shepard Gilman re. his candidacy for Congress; opposition to candidacy of Thomas Seymour., Jan. 12, 1863, March 11,1863; (2 items) (Box 17, Folder G)
  - George Shepard Gilman Civil War correspondence., 1861-63; (3 items) (Box 17, Folder H)
  - George Shepard Gilman Political correspondence., 1861,64,84; (5 items) (Box 17, Folder I)
  - George Shepard Gilman mss notes speech to Wide Awakes., [18--?]; (2 items) (Box 17, Folder J)
  - Republican Party: election 1860: correspondence Republican Congressional Election Committee., (4 items) (Box 17, Folder K)
  - Republican Party: canvass book-Hartford County., 1859-60; (1 item) (Box 17, Folder L)
  - Republican Party: canvassing lists city of Hartford., 1860; (20 items) (Box 17, Folder M)
  - Republican Party: correspondence with town committees., Jan-March 1860; (15 items) (Box 17, Folder N)
    Some correspondents: James Dixon, N. D. Sperry [letter re Lincoln coming], Oliver Stanley, H.W. Starkweather, Dwight Loomis, D. Wadsworth.
  - Republican Party: election 1860, correspondence town committees., March 1860; (15 items) (Box 17, Folder 0)
  - Republican Party: election 1860, correspondence with town committees., March-October 1860; (12 items) (Box 17, Folder P)
  - Republican Party: election 1864, correspondence with town committees., Feb.-Oct.1864; (15 items) (Box 17, Folder Q)
  - Republican Party: election 1864, correspondence with town committees., Oct.-Feb.1865; (10 items) (Box 17, Folder R)
  - Republican Party: correspondence., 1878-1880; (8 items) (Box 17, Folder S)
  - Alphabetical list of electors entitled to vote in the Third District of the town of Hartford at the presidential election Nov. 6, 1860 and at the annual Town Meeting next following. [printed]. (Box OV 1, Folder A)
  - Alphabetical list of the electors of the City of Hartford entitled to vote at the City Election in the Fourth Ward on Monday, April 3, 1863. [printed]., (2 items) (Box OV 1, Folder B)
  - George Shepard Gilman Diary., 1861-68; (l items) (Box 18, Folder A)
  - George Shepard Gilman Diaries., 1865, 66, 67.; (3 items) (Box 18, Folder B)
  - George Shepard Gilman Diaries, (pocket)., 1872,1883,1884; (3 items) (Box 18, Folder C)
  - George Shepard Gilman Account book., 1851-54; (l items) (Box 18, Folder D)
  - George Shepard Gilman Account books (pocket)., 1872-1886; (3 items) (Box 18, Folder E)
  - George Shepard Gilman Account book (pocket)., (l items) (Box 18, Folder F)
  - George Shepard Gilman Connecticut Mutual Expense Account book for Pennsylvania and Kentucky., 1865-1885; (l items) (Box 18, Folder G)
  - George Shepard Gilman Account book., 1860-1870; (l items) (Box 18, Folder H)
  - George Shepard Gilman Loose papers found in account books and diaries., (15 items) (Box 18, Folder I)
- V. Hills Family Papers
  - Hills family deeds, inventory, mortgages., 1829, 1830, 1832, 1847, 1848, 1857, 1859, 1886, 1919; (9 items) (Box 19, Folder A)
  - Horace W. Hills, prescriptions., [18--?]; (12 items) (Box 19, Folder B)
  - Horace W. Hills, receipts 1836-1863., (49 items) (Box 19, Folder C)
  - Horace W. Hills, Passport,signed by Lewis Cass., 1860; (1 item) (Box 19, Folder D)
  - Horace W. Hills, certificate of draft substitution., 1862,1864; (2 items) (Box 19, Folder E)
  - Horace W. Hills, dog license., 1879; (1 item) (Box 19, Folder E-1)
  - Horace W. Hills, receipts and certificates 1864-1889 [membership cemetery association; Hartford City Guard]., 1865,1870; (10 items) (Box 19, Folder F)
  - Horace W. Hills, social correspondence [thank yous and invitations]., 1862-1870; (26 items) (Box 19, Folder G)
  - Horace W. Hills, correspondence., 1880, 1886; (21 item) (Box 19, Folder H)
  - Horace W. Hills, Putnam and Earle case., 1882-84; (38 items) (Box 19, Folder I)
  - Horace W. Hills, old stock certificates., 1860-65; (23 items) (Box 19, Folder J)
  - Horace W. Hills Family, Inventory of assets., 1888-1891; (26 items) (Box 19, Folder K)
  - Hills, Eliza, release of real estate holdings to children; will., 1872-1860; (3 items) (Box 19, Folder L)
  - Hills estate distribution., 1894; (1 item) (Box 19, Folder M)
  - Hills, Isaac, family correspondence, 1868-1874; (9 items) (Box 19, Folder N)
  - Hills, Isaac, family receipts., 1837-1891; (285 items) (Box 19, Folder O.-X)
  - Account books., 1853, 1858, 1886; (4 items) (Box 20, Folder A)
  - Horace W. H. Diary, trip to Europe., 1860; (11 item) (Box 20, Folder B)
  - Horace W. H. Diary., 1860; (7 items) (Box 20, Folder C)
  - Horace W. H. will, [mss. copy]., 1890; (10 items) (Box 20, Folder D)
  - Horace W. H. estate, E.H. Gilman executor, documents., 1890-1894; (108 items) (Box 20, Folder E- I)
  - H. Hubbard Hills, estate Isaac Hills, executor. Leonard Hills, estate, receipts, account book., 1846-48; (14 items) (Box 20, Folder F)
  - HILLS, Ellery, Guardian, Ellen Hills, probate certificate, 1860; account sheets, 1860-61., (3 items) (Box 20, Folder G)
  - HILLS, I and Sons: agreement of settlement, 1894; account book, 1893., (7 items) (Box 20, Folder H)
  - HILLS, I. and Sons: estate: Buildings 26-28 Asylum Street; construction contract, leases, correspondence., 1882-1888; (10 items) (Box 20, Folder I)
  - Building on Asylum Street (drawing)., 1882; (1 item) (Box 20, Folder J)
- VI. Ellen Hills Gilman
  - Gilman, Ellen Hills: Correspondence from George Shepard Gilman and Julia Hills Prentice., 1867; (16 items) (Box 21, Folder A)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence., 1870-1888; (94 items) (Box 21, Folder B-G)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence to and from George Hills Gilman., 1889; (7 items) (Box 21, Folder H)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence family., 1889; (29 items) (Box 21, Folder I)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence general., 1889; (39 items) (Box 21, Folder J)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence general., 1889-95; (41 items) (Box 21, Folder K-L)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence from George Hills Gilman., 1890-96; (25 items) (Box 21, Folder M)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence general., 1896; (42 items) (Box 21, Folder N)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence with E.P. Parker and family., 1880-96; (16 items) (Box 21, Folder 0)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence Julia Gilman., 1897; (6 items) (Box 22, Folder A)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence., 1898-99; (29 items) (Box 22, Folder B-C)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence from Julia Hills Gilman; to George Hills Gilman., 1900 from Elliot P. John [re Julia Hills Gilman]., (11 items) (Box 22, Folder D)
  - Ellen H. Gilman correspondence., 1900-1903; (198 items) (Box 22, Folder E-J)
  - Ellen H. Gilman Correspondence general., 1904-1910; (186 items) (Box 23, Folder A-F)
  - Ellen H. Gilman miscellaneous notes and writings., [18--?]; (18 items) (Box 23, Folder G)
  - Ellen H. Gilman European trip, correspondence., 1890; (24 items) (Box 23, Folder H)
  - Ellen H. Gilman European trip, correspondence., 1890; (47 items) (Box 23, Folder I)
  - Ellen H. Gilman European trip, bills and business correspondence., 1890; (45 items) (Box 23, Folder J)
  - Ellen H. Gilman European trip; accounts and memorabilia., 1890; (27 items) (Box 23, Folder K)
  - Ellen H. Gilman invitations and announcements-family and official., [18--?]; (30 items) (Box 23, Folder L)
  - Ellen H. Gilman greeting cards., [18--?]; (28 items) (Box 23, Folder M)
  - George Shepard Gilman and Ellen H. Gilman receipts., 1863-1886; (256 items) (Box 24, Folder A-N)
  - Ellen H. Gilman receipts., 1887-1894; (228 items) (Box 24a, Folder O-V)
  - Ellen H. Gilman receipts., 1895-1903; (337 items) (Box 25, Folder A-H)
  - Ellen H. Gilman cancelled checks Connecticut Trust and Safe Co., 1874-1885; (approx. 200 items) (Box 26, Folder A)
  - Ellen H. Gilman cancelled checks and statements Connecticut Trust and Safe Deposit Co., approx. 400; 1885-Jan.1890 (Box 26, Folder B)
  - Ellen H. Gilman cancelled checks and statements Connecticut Trust and Safe Deposit Co., 1895-1901; (approx 900 items) (Box 26, Folder C)
  - Ellen H. Gilman cancelled checks and statements Connecticut Trust and Safe Deposit Co., 1895-1901; (approx 500 items) (Box 26, Folder D)
  - Ellen H. Gilman Bank books., 1887-1909; (5 items) (Box 27, Folder A)
  - Ellen H. Gilman check books., 1877-1898; (19 items) (Box 27, Folder B)
  - Hills, Horace W. and Hills, I and Sons Estate: cancelled checks, State Bank, Ellen H. Gilman executor., 1890-1893; (200 items) (Box 27, Folder C)
  - Stock certificates., 1860-1881; (19 items) (Box 27, Folder D)
  - Soldiers Family Relief [Society) minutes., Nov.18,1864-April 1865; (2 items) (Box 28, Folder A)
  - 149 Lafayette Street: Deeds and Agreement., 1865; (7 items) (Box 28, Folder B)
  - 149 Lafayette Street itemized bill contractor., 1896; (20 items) (Box 28, Folder C)
  - Specifications for house for Mrs. G.S. Gilman., 1896; (18 items) (Box 28, Folder D)
  - 63 Lafayette Street: History removal house., 1896; (2 items) (Box 28, Folder E)
  - Franklin House Papers; 146 Washington Street: sales agreement, deed sketch, blue print drawing of front exterior of house., 1883-1903; (5 items) (Box 28, Folder F)
  - Franklin House, 146 Washington Street: titles, correspondence, probate documents., 1882-83, 1903-1912; 16 (Box 28, Folder G)
  - Architectural plans 146 Washington Street., 1866-1928; (1 items) (Box 28, Folder H)
  - 6 Charter Oak Place, James H. Knight, receipted bills., 1902-3; (27 items) (Box 28, Folder I)
- VII. George Hills Gilman
  - Wadsworth Street School Report cards., 1878-81; (4 items) (Box 29, Folder A)
  - Hartford Public High School., 1881-1884; (17 items) (Box 29, Folder A-1)
  - George Hills Gilman. Report cards, Hartford Public High School., 1881-82; (17 items) (Box 29, Folder B)
  - George Hills Gilman. Report cards, Hartford Public High School., 1883-84; (23 items) (Box 29, Folder C)
  - George Hills Gilman. Essays, Hartford Public High School., 1882-84; (23 items) (Box 29, Folder D)
  - George Hills Gilman. Graduation, Hartford Public High School., 1885; (11 items) (Box 29, Folder E)
  - George Hills Gilman. Dance cards, Hartford Public High School., 1885-86, 1892-93; (3 items) (Box 29, Folder F)
  - George Hills Gilman. Valentines., 1922; (28 items) (Box 29, Folder G)
  - George Hills Gilman. Yale College bills., 1887-1890; (18 items) (Box 29, Folder H)
  - George Hills Gilman. Psi Upsilon membership., 1888; (3 items) (Box 29, Folder H-1)
  - George Hills Gilman. Notice of election to Common Council., 1894; (2 items) (Box 29, Folder H-2)
  - George Hills Gilman. correspondence re automobiles., 1909-1912; (13 items) (Box 29, Folder I)
  - J. George Hills Gilman. Dauntless Club papers., 1905-17; (11 items) (Box 29, Folder J)
  - George Hills Gilman. Dauntless Club papers., 1917-1918; (62 items) (Box 29, Folder K)
  - George Hills Gilman. correspondence., 1897, 1909-10; (64 items) (Box 29, Folder L)
  - George Hills Gilman. correspondence., 1911-12; (37 items) (Box 29, Folder M)
  - George Hills Gilman. correspondence W.R. Sill., 1920; (6 items) (Box 29, Folder M-1)
  - George Hills Gilman. wills, estate, deed, receipt., 1874-1911; (7 items) (Box 29, Folder N)
  - George Hills Gilman. essays, speeches, skit, poem., 1889; (5 items) (Box 29, Folder 0)
  - George Hills Gilman. memorabilia., 1919, 1920; (5 items) (Box 29, Folder P)
- VIII. Mabel Goodrich Gilman
  - Correspondence re Webb house., 1916; (12 items) (Box 30, Folder A)
  - Correspondence and receipts., 1921-1936; (4 items) (Box 30, Folder A-1)
  - Mabel Goodrich Gilman: social and travel diaries., 1899-1952; (5 items) (Box 30, Folder A-2)
  - Civil defense certificates., 1942,1945; (2 items) (Box 30, Folder B)
  - Mabel Goodrich Gilman Records of entertaining., 1939-1953; (31 item) (Box 30, Folder B-1)
  - Mabel Goodrich Gilman Goodrich mss. genealogical notes and Correspondence., 1930; (42 items) (Box 30, Folder C)
  - Mabel Goodrich Gilman Goodrich Castle, photos, prints, tss. history of Goodrich family and castle from Goodrich genealogy pp.37-41)., 1936; (9 items) (Box 30, Folder D)
  - Mabel Goodrich Gilman Beldon Family notes., [19--?]; (3 items) (Box 30, Folder E)
  - Boardman Family: description armorial bearings., [19--?]; (1 item) (Box 30, Folder F)
  - Butler Family: genealogical notes., 1944; (39 items) (Box 30, Folder G)
  - Churchill Family: genealogical notes., 1898, 1934; (39 items) (Box 30, Folder H)
  - Crane Family: genealogical notes 1852., [19--?]; (10 items) (Box 30, Folder I)
  - Gilman Family: genealogical notes including chart and coat of arms., 1911-1978; (25 items) (Box 30, Folder J)
  - Hanmer Family: genealogical notes and tss. history Hanmer Family., [19--?]; (10 items) (Box 30, Folder K)
  - Hanmer and Wills Family genealogical notes 1837, 1845, 1903, 1932., (28 items) (Box 30, Folder L)
  - Hills Family: genealogical note sand chart., [19--?]; (1 item) (Box 30, Folder M)
  - Judd Family: genealogical notes, 1856., [19--?]; (1 item) (Box 30, Folder N)
  - Orcott Family: genealogical notes., [19--?] (Box 30, Folder 0)
  - Roberts Family: genealogical notes., [19--?]; (3 items) (Box 30, Folder P)
  - Stillman Family: genealogical notes., [19--?]; (9 items) (Box 30, Folder Q)
  - Welles Family: genealogical notes., [19--?]; (2 items) (Box 30, Folder R)
  - Goodrich and Hanmer families: genealogical chart., [19--?]; (1 item) (Box OV II)
- IX. Memorabilia
  - General convention of the Friends of Domestic Industry, New York, Oct. 26, 1831 printed report signed "William C. Gilman"., (l items) (Box 31, Folder A)
  - Wash drawing of house; cartoon re bicycle., [19--?]; (2 items) (Box 31, Folder B)
  - Souvenir menu: Farmington Valley Polo Assoc. 1940; Notice of partnership Gilman and Marks, 1935., 1935-1940; (3 items) (Box 31, Folder C)
  - Scrapbook: Gilman, Hills and others obituaries., 1886-1889; (l items) (Box 31, Folder D)
  - Souvenir menu: testimonial to J. Watson Beach., 1936; (1 item) (Box 31, Folder E)
  - Accession sheets identifying photographs in photographic dept. Connecticut Historical Society. (Box 31, Folder F)